DARWIN ANDERSON Software Engineer Full-Stack Developer

Personal Information

ADDRESS

1021 Grandeview Blvd. Apt 216 Huntsville, AL. 35824

→ PHONE

256-275-1628

■ EMAIL

darwin.p.anderson@gmail.com

in LINKEDIN

darwin-anderson-38a583173

⇔ GITHUB

github.com/darwinpanderson

PROFICIENCIES

Languages & Frameworks

- HTML/CSS/SASS
- PHP, Django, RoR
- MySQL, PostgreSQL, Mongo
- Javascript / NodeJS
- AngularJS, VueJS
- Python 2 & 3
- Golang

Skill Proficiencies

- Solution Analysis
- UI/UX Design
- REST API design
- Full-Stack Deployment
- Database Administration
- GIT Repository Management
- Project Planning and Management

CERTIFICATIONS & ACCOLADES

Certified Scrum Master (CSM)

Tech Mentor

NASA Space Apps Challenge 2019

Tech Mentor

Hudson Alpha Tech Challenge 2020

I am a Software Developer with nine years of experience specializing in web application development, data ETL processes, DevOps, server administration, database architecture, continuous integration and delivery(CI/CD), and zero-downtime deployments. I have developed and implemented RESTful API modules, accounting systems, integrated payment processing modules, database schemas, analytics tools, social media integrations, system redesigns, and microservices for both small and large scale projects. My greatest strengths are my analytical and organizational skills, which enable me to properly plan projects with AGILE methodologies and convey concepts across all levels of experience and technical acumen.

EXPERIENCE

2019 - Current	Senior Software Engineer / Scrum Master
	Imagehawk, Inc Huntsville, AL
	 Developed merge and operations processes for codebase updates Primary developer for project merging deviated development branches back to single master Primary developer for multi-disciplinary clinic management product Met with clients alongside CEO and COO as technical advisor Assessed and evaluated data architecture and developed new data schemas for future implementation Developed, implemented, and facilitated various Agile practices and Scrum ceremonies within the Engineering team Created issue templates, planned sprint scopes, and assisted the Product Owner within numerous JIRA projects Mentored engineers on new technologies/practices, and helped facilitate the removal of blocking obstacles
2018 - 2019	Software Engineer
	Partcycle Technologies - Florence, AL
	 Developed ETL tools and processes that evaluated over one million inventory items nightly Developed numerous features for online marketplace servicing both consumer and commercial customers Utilized CI/CD techniques to deploy update patches hourly Leveraged AWS and Heroku resources to develop DevOps processes and reporting tools Attended conferences and functions alongside CEO and COO as technical advisor
2013 - 2018	SENIOR FULL STACK DEVELOPER
	IMS Enterprises, Inc Florence, AL
	 Developed tools for internal administration and customer support usage Implemented updates to legacy systems to bring them up to security and W3C standards Lead developer for several account management and registration systems Primary DevOps engineer for numerous client server environments Project Manager for 47inf.org site redesign

EDUCATION

2009 - 2011

NORTHWEST SHOALS COMMUNITY COLLEGE

Associates of Applied Science - Computer Science